apl.com 2013-06-14

# APL: Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy 

**Contents:**[ Definition |Information Collected on the Site](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#information) | [Use of Cookies and Log Files](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#useofcookies) | [Security](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#security) | [Provision of Information to Others](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#provision) | [Links to Other Sites](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#links) | [Additional Information](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#additional) | [Updating Your Personal Information, Opt Out Policy](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#updating) | [Contact Us  
](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#contact)  
**Definition:** The terms “we”, “us” and “our” are used to refer to Neptune Orient Lines Limited (NOL) and the group of companies constituting its direct and indirect subsidiaries worldwide, including without limitation, American President Lines, Ltd, APL Co. Pte Ltd, APL Logistics Ltd and Eagle Marine Services, Ltd. 

We are committed to maintaining the privacy of users who access our Web site (the "Site"). This Privacy Policy Statement (the "Privacy Policy") explains the types of information we gather and what we do with it. By using the Site, you agree to the terms and policies described in this Privacy Policy.

**1\. Information Collected on the Site**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
We do not request or require any information from anonymous visitors to the Site. We collect personal information only from those users who wish to conduct business transactions on the Site and who have registered on the Site ("Registered Users"). Personal information means information about an identifiable individual and may include your name, address, telephone and fax number, e-mail address, financial information, such as a credit card number and employment-related information, such as may be found on a resume or job application. Personal information does not include business contact information (e.g. office address, telephone number) in those jurisdictions which do not recognize such information as being personal information. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any User ID which may be assigned to you, as well as any account number, account name, or passwords, if applicable, for the services you utilize through the Site.

We need the information Registered Users supply for (a) personal identification, (b) to allow us to contact you for service(s) or opportunities as requested by you, such as customer service or information about a job opportunity if you have submitted a resume on-line, (c) to make improvements to materials or products offered on the Site and to the Site in general, and (d) to enable Registered Users to access the functionalities described on the Site, including without limitation, tracking shipments, viewing outstanding charges , applying for employment, and obtaining other user-specific information. Your e-mail address is collected to send you an e-mail message confirming your new member registration as well as confirmations for other services you transact with us on-line. In addition, we may use such information (i) for demographic profiling, ad targeting, statistical analysis, to conduct surveys and similar marketing activities; (ii) to investigate violations of either the Privacy Policy or the "Terms of Use"; and (iii) to notify Registered Users about important changes to the Site or promotions or opportunities. You may always decline to receive these messages by following the process to [Opt Out](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#updating) as described below or as described within a particular message.

We will deactivate accounts of Registered Users that have been inactive for an extended period of time.

Registered Users may access and change their information at any time via the Site as described in Section 7 below. 

**2\. Use of Cookies and Log Files**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
The Site does not use persistent or stored cookies; however, it does use temporary or per-session cookies. Temporary or per-session cookies act as a randomly generated session ID; they last only while the Registered User is logged onto the Web site, and are cancelled at the end of the session (i.e., the Registered User logs out of the Site or closes their Web browser program). The Site uses temporary cookies for security purposes. Each time a Registered User logs onto the Site, the Site server generates a temporary session ID, which it associates with the user's login name, password and computer during that particular session. This allows the Registered User to move from page to page in the Site during a specific session, without having to re-enter the user login name and/or password. The temporary cookie allows the Site server to continuously verify that the user is a permitted user as the user moves from page to page during a specific session. When the Registered User logs out of the Site the temporary session ID is cancelled, and is removed from the temporary memory of the user's computer; and the association in the Site server between the temporary session ID and the specific user login name and password is also terminated. 

We also use log files for anonymous site usage analysis. A "log file" is a data file that records a Registered User's activity while using the Site. 

**3\. Security**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
We store information received from Registered Users on secure computers. Only a small number of our employees and/or contractors have physical access to these computers. We use firewalls and other security technology to prevent our computers from being accessed by unauthorized persons.

While we have taken measures to protect Registered Users' information, please know that (i) no computer system is immune from intrusion; and (ii) information transmitted to the Site may need to pass through many systems in order to process such information. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the absolute security or confidentiality of information transmitted to the Site. 

**4\. Provision of Information to Others**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
When you submit personal information through this Site, you understand and agree that this information may be transferred across national boundaries and may be stored and processed in any of the countries in which we transact business, including, without limitation, the United States. You also acknowledge that in certain countries or with respect to certain activities, the collection, transferring, storage, and processing of your information may be undertaken by our trusted vendors. Such vendors are bound by contract not to use your personal information for their own purposes and to treat the information as confidential. 

We have established relationships with various service providers whose services are available to you from this Site or from Web sites that are linked to this Site or who support us by providing services which are transparent to you. Typically, these providers offer services that our customers might find useful, such as those that can be used in conjunction with our services and products. In order to use those services, you may be required to provide personal information to the providers. Unless expressly provided to the contrary, personal information that you provide while you are visiting a provider's Web site will be subject to the privacy policy posted on such site, and personal information that you provide while on this Site in conjunction with a provider's service will be subject to this Privacy Policy. You should be aware that our agreements with these service providers often provide that they will share with us personal information collected from you. In such instances, we may use this information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

When ordering products or services on the Site, you may be asked to provide a credit card number. Depending upon the activity, some of the information that we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity.

If we sell assets (or the assets of a division or subsidiary) to another entity, or we (or a division or subsidiary) are acquired by, or merged with, another entity, we may provide to such entity customer information that is related to that part of our business that was sold to or merged with the other entity without your consent.

Other than as described in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise specifically communicated to you by us, we do not provide information supplied by users to any third parties, except where law, court order, or governmental authority requires or based upon the good faith belief that disclosure is necessary including, without limitation, to protect our rights when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or causing harm to third parties. 

**5\. Links to Other Sites**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
The Site may contain links to Web sites other than our own and for which we are not responsible. Such Web Sites may collect personal information from you. These Web sites may send their own cookies to you, and may collect information and use it in a way inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. In such instances, unless expressly provided to the contrary, the collection and use of your personal information will be governed by the privacy policy applicable to that Web site which should identify the entity that is collecting your personal information.  Unless we explicitly state otherwise, such references in no way indicate our endorsement, recommendation or preference of any such products, services or information contained on any other site. 

**6\. Additional Information**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
We may alter, update or otherwise change this Privacy Policy at any time to reflect material changes in the way we use your information. Any such changes will be posted on this page. You should periodically check this Privacy Policy to review the current terms and guidelines applicable to your use.  Your continued use of the Site following the posting of such changes will indicate your full acceptance of those changes.

**7\. Updating Your Personal Information, Opt Out Policy**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
At any time, you can access and correct your personal information and privacy preferences, including exercising your right to unsubscribe as a Registered User of the Site by sending an e-mail to [homeport@apl.com](mailto:homeport@apl.com). As a Registered User, you will occasionally receive e-mail messages from us as described in [Section 1](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#information) above. If you would prefer not to receive these messages you may opt out by following the instructions within the e-mail message, changing your preferences or (for HomePort related emails) by contacting us at [homeport@apl.com](mailto:homeport@apl.com). We reserve the right to limit certain services to Registered Users who will accept e-mail messages. Non-Registered Users of Homeport can access and correct their personal information and privacy preferences with us by contacting [global_marketing@nol.com.sg. ](mailto:global_marketing@nol.com.sg.%20)

**8\. Contact Us**       [Top](http://www.apl.com/help_center/html/privacy_policy.html#top)  
If you have any inquiries or concerns with respect to your personal information or you have other related inquiries or concerns, you may write to us at the following address:

Group General Counsel  
Neptune Orient Lines Limited  
456 Alexandra Road  
#06-00 NOL Building  
Singapore 119962  
Email: [group_legal@nol.com.sg](mailto:group_legal@nol.com.sg)

In your letter, please describe in as much detail as possible the nature of your inquiry or the ways in which you believe that this Privacy Policy has not been complied with so that we may investigate your inquiry. 

Please note that if you provide us with inconsistent privacy preferences (for example, by indicating on one occasion that third parties may contact you with marketing offers and indicating on another occasion that they may not), we cannot guarantee that your most recent privacy preference will be honored.
